I've killed 13 people up until now.
我至今總共殺了13個人
I consider myself stronger than any random idiot off the street.
我自認為我比街上任何一位 無名小卒都來得強壯
Killing is fun.
殺人很有趣
Talk about the look on that face
說到那個狂妄的小首領
of the bratty little jarl.
臨死之前的表情
That's why I know...
所以我知道
This row of enemies
我眼前的
in front of me...
這一排敵人...
I'm scared! I'm scared!
我好害怕...
Damn it! They are enjoying this!
該死,他們很享受這一切
Damn it!
該死
Gudmund!
古德孟德!
My legs...
我的腿...
Badger is going to be killed!
獾會被殺死
I can't believe it!
我真不敢相信
How can he get so close to the Jomsvikings?
他竟然能夠與約姆戰士近距離對打?
Boss!
老大!
Fox! Take Badger and return to the fort!
狐,帶著獾一起往堡壘撤退
I'm ordering the entire army to retreat!
我下令全員撤退
You must be kidding! I can still fight!
你在開什麼玩笑?我還能打
That's enough, Badger. Take a look around you.
夠了,獾,你看清楚周圍的狀況吧
Damn it! They need this many people to die just to realize how unmatched they are.
該死,一定要死了這麼多人 他們才能明白雙方的實力有多懸殊
Retreat!
撤退!
- What? Retreat? - Yes!
-什麼?撤退? -太好了!
Don't stay together! Spread out and run!
別聚在一起,散開,往不同方向撤退
Wait! My legs...
等等,我的腿...
Did you say, "retreat"?
你剛剛說:“撤退”?
I did not give that order! Shame on you!
不是我下的命令,你們真可恥
How can you call yourselves Nordic men?
你們有什麼資格自稱為北方人?
Wait for me!
等等我
I told you not to run away!
我說了,不准逃跑
Do you expect me to write off your debt with this level of service?
你就盡了這麼一點責任 還敢期望我一筆勾銷你的債務?
Who cares about the debt. You are done for, Ketil.
誰還在乎欠你多少錢啊? 你完蛋了,凱特爾
Does this give you a little taste of what it's like to be poor like us?
這是不是讓你嘗到了 跟我們一樣窮的滋味?
No matter how unfair it is,
不管有多不公平
you shouldn't have disobeyed the king.
你都不應該忤逆國王
Just as we obeyed you.
就跟我們不該忤逆你一樣
Power is justice, Ketil.
權力就是正義,凱特爾
This world exists for people who are more powerful than you.
這個世界是為了 比你更有權有勢的人而存在著
They're here!
他們來了
- What's wrong, Wulf? - Your Majesty.
-沃爾夫,怎麼了? -陛下
A subordinate of mine just killed a man whom I think was Ketil.
我的一位下屬剛剛殺了一個人 我認為那個人是凱特爾
That was a poor decision.
真是錯得離譜
Did I not order them to capture him?
我不是下令要活捉他嗎?
Yes, I am terribly sorry.
對,我實在深感抱歉
I will go check on that.
我會去確認清楚
The Jomsvikings are killing those who escape, which is also against my orders.
約姆戰士殺了那些逃兵 這一樣是違背我的命令
- Tell Floki to stop going after them. - Yes.
-告訴弗洛基,要他停止追殺他們 -遵命
For some reason, the captain is walking away.
不知為何,將領走遠了
It's my chance!
我的機會來了
Go!
衝
Be careful with the bodies. We will return them to their families...
小心處理那些屍首 我們要把屍首還給他們的家人
Canute!
庫奴特
Off with your head!
我要你人頭落地
Thorgil! Where did you come from!
托爾吉爾,你是從哪裡冒出來的?
From the underworld.
從地底世界
What a surprise.
我還真意外
Who knew you could withstand my attack.
沒想到你竟然能夠擋下我那一劍
You've improved, Your Majesty.
你進步了,陛下
My right hand is limp.
我的右手麻了
Did I sprain it just now?
是剛剛扭傷的嗎?
That's the spirit!
這樣就對了!
That's how a commander should be!
指揮官就該有這種膽勢
I'd love to play with you,
我很樂意陪你玩玩
but I'm sorry. I don't have much time.
但很抱歉,我沒那麼多時間
Let's start over. Off with your head!
從頭來過吧,我要你人頭落地
You bastard! How dare you treat His Majesty that way!
你這個渾球,竟敢對陛下如此無禮
Die!
去死吧!
Your Majesty, please hand the sword to me and stay back!
陛下,請把劍給我,您退到我身後
Damn it!
該死
Royal guards, head back! Protect the king!
皇家警衛,快回頭,保護國王
Wait, Thorgil!
等等,托爾吉爾
Don't go after him, Wulf. You are heavily injured.
別追他了,沃爾夫,你傷得很重
It was partly due to my carelessness, but more than that, he is a bold man.
一部分的原因是我自己太大意 但更大的原因是他膽識過人
I want him as my subordinate again.
我要他再度效忠於我
Royal guards, return to your places!
皇家警衛,回到原本的崗位上
King Canute was attacked.
庫奴特王被攻擊了
All of you, go back!
全體回頭
Run! Hurry up!
跑快點
- Your Majesty!
-陛下
What?
什麼?
Who would do...? Was it Thorgil?
誰能夠...難道是托爾吉爾?
That was close.
有夠驚險
Master! Are you alive?
主人,你還活著嗎?
Good.
很好
Those soldiers
我想那些士兵
didn't know what the master looked like, I guess.
不知道主人的樣貌
You are lucky.
你很幸運
Damn, you're heavy.
該死,你好重
Don't even think about taking the easy way out by dying.
休想選擇死亡這條輕鬆的路來解脫
You will take responsibility as the commander of a defeated army,
你得以戰敗軍團將領的身分負起責任
Iron Fist Ketil.
鐵拳凱特爾
I hear those sounds...
我聽到那些聲音了...
The sounds I heard
我聽到了
when my village was burned down.
當我的村莊被燒毀時的聲音
The sound of the world falling apart.
世界崩塌的聲音
They are fighting a war, aren't they?
他們在打仗,對吧?
It's okay. Don't worry.
沒事的,別擔心
We're not slaves anymore.
我們再也不是奴隸了
We will leave this farm.
我們會離開這座農場
That battle has nothing to do with us.
那場戰爭與我們無關
After we leave this place,
我們離開這裡之後
where will we go?
要去哪裡?
Let's go to my village.
去我的村莊吧
It's a bit cold, but it's a nice place.
那裡有點冷,但是個好地方
Are there
那裡
slaves there?
有奴隸嗎?
war?
有戰爭嗎?
There was fighting in the past,
過去發生過戰事
and I would be lying if I told you that there will be none in the future.
如果我告訴妳未來不會再有戰爭 那我就是在說謊
I will not go.
我不要去
I am going somewhere else.
我要去別的地方
Gardar and the children...
哥達和孩子...
I had them wait for me...
他們在等著我...
because I wanted to say thank you.
我只是...來向你們道謝的
Thank you, Einar and Thorfinn.
謝謝你們,埃納爾和托爾芬
Thank you.
謝謝
The whole time,
這一段時間
it felt as though I was lost inside a nightmare.
我覺得自己彷彿迷失在惡夢裡
I was all alone.
我形單影隻
But...
但是...
our morning chats...
我們會在早上聊天
Einar's
埃納爾的...
stories...
故事
No! Arnheid!
不行,阿奴納!
Stay strong! Arnheid!
撐住啊,阿奴納!
Arnheid!
阿奴納!
Remember you said that you were going to
妳不是說了要保護
protect your unborn child? Arnheid!
妳肚子裡的孩子嗎,阿奴納?
This child already went ahead of me.
這個孩子已經先走一步了
All of them died.
他們全都死了
All of the people who were dear to me.
我最親愛的人全都死了
What is the point of living any more than this?
我繼續活著還有什麼意義?
There is nothing here anymore.
這裡什麼也不剩了
Why do I have to live?
我為什麼還要活下去?
I...
我...
Because... to me you are...
因為...妳對我而言...
Arnheid.
阿奴納
- Arnheid! - Move, Einar!
-阿奴納 -讓開,埃納爾
My father once taught me this method to bring the dead back to life.
我父親教過我 用這個方法讓人死而復生
Einar, talk to her! In a loud voice!
埃納爾,跟她說話,大聲說
Arnheid! Don't go!
阿奴納,別走
I... really like you.
我...真的很喜歡妳
I need you!
我需要妳
I want you to laugh at my stories again.
我希望妳能再次被我的故事逗笑
Stay alive and once again...
撐下去,讓我們再一次...
Please live with me!
請跟我一起生活!
Please live!
拜託妳活下來!
Einar, that's enough.
埃納爾,夠了
Far to the west...
在遙遠的西方...
beyond the vast sea,
越過了浩瀚的海洋
there is a land called Vinland.
有個地方叫文蘭
The land is warm and bountiful.
是個溫暖美麗的地方
It is so far that neither slave traders nor the flames of war
它位於十分遙遠的地方 因此奴隸販子和戰火...
can reach.
抵達不了
There, I am sure you will be able to live
在那裡,我保證妳能夠過著
without feeling any pain.
沒有苦痛的生活
Arnheid,
阿奴納
come with us to that land.
跟我們一起去那個地方吧
Let's create a land of peace in Vinland.
讓我們在文蘭創造一個和平之地
You guys...
你們...
Why are you still here?
為什麼還待在這裡?
Stop, Einar!
住手,埃納爾
Ketil!
凱特爾
Because of you, Arnheid...
因為你,阿奴納...
I will kill you! I will kill you!
我要殺了你...
Stop it, Einar!
別這樣,埃納爾!
Killing the master will do nothing.
殺了主人也於事無補
I see... So Arnheid...
我明白了,所以阿奴納...
Wake up, Einar!
醒醒吧,埃納爾!
Please!
拜託你!
Einar!
埃納爾!
Einar...
埃納爾
your anger
即使你殺了主人
will not subside even if you kill the master.
也無法平息你的怒火
Anger will manifest anger
怒火只會帶來更大的怒火
and people will keep dying. That's all.
導致傷亡不斷,就是這樣
I was living
我過去一直活在
that nightmare this whole time.
這種惡夢裡
Please, Einar.
拜託你,埃納爾
Please don't put yourself under the same curse as me.
拜託你,別讓自己 陷入跟我一樣的詛咒
Dad...
爸...
I know. Get ready to set sail for me.
我知道,準備揚帆啟航
God
上帝
must be watching us even as we speak.
一定在看著我們 當我們在說話的時候
As we lose our friends,
當我們失去朋友的時候
as parents and children kill each other,
當父母和孩子互相殘殺的時候
He is looking down upon
祂從高高在上的地方
all of that from high above.
俯視著我們
Thorfinn...
托爾芬
Wait. Where are you going?
等等,你要去哪裡?
Wait! What are you planning to do?
等等,你有什麼打算?
I am going to meet with Canute.
我要去見庫奴特
The master was still alive.
主人還活著
He's not even captured.
他甚至沒被抓走
It's not settled yet.
事情還沒結束
I might be able to prevent any more deaths.
我或許能夠阻止更多傷亡
That's ridiculous! Let's get away from here right now.
太荒唐了,我們快點離開這個地方
Why do you have to go that far?
你為什麼要拿自己的性命開玩笑?
Thorfinn!
托爾芬!
This time... This time...
這一次...
Let me finally take you back to Iceland.
就讓我帶你回冰島吧
Please!
求求你
Remember you told me a long time ago?
還記得你在很久以前 告訴過我的事嗎?
That our ancestors
我們的祖先
ran away
為了躲避戰爭
to escape from the fighting and ended up in Iceland.
逃離家園,最後來到了冰島
At that time,
那個時候
I thought
我心想
that was so uncool.
他們也太遜了吧?
But now, I feel so proud of them.
但現在,我好以他們為傲
Thorfinn...
托爾芬...
When I took a quick glance, Canute only had about 100 soldiers.
我掃視了一下 庫奴特大概只有一百名士兵
Even if worse comes to worst,
就算狀況一發不可收拾
I will be able to at least come back alive.
我至少還能夠活著回來
I'll be on the ship
我會待在船上
and ready to set sail at any time.
做好立刻開船的準備
Don't push yourself.
不要太勉強自己
We will return to Iceland no matter what!
無論如何,我們一定要回到冰島
Thorfinn!
托爾芬
"Courage."
第21集:勇氣
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻譯:歐德慧